

# **Domenico Camasta**

✓ domenicocamasta@gmail.com 📞 3701522690 🔮 Via F. Baracca 8 🛗 29/12/1983

■ Italian

♣ He/Him ★ portfolio.devcrumbs.com ♠ d-cmst

#### **Profile**

I'm a software developer with over 10 years of experience building web applications using technologies like Python, JavaScript, React, and Node. is. My expertise includes designing and implementing RESTful APIs and optimizing database queries for performance.

# **Professional Experience**

**Developer,** *UserTesting* □

2018 - 12/2022

Creating and executing usability tests to evaluate the ease of use, efficiency, and overall user experience of software products: designing test plans, coding test scripts, recruiting test participants, and analyzing test results.

UK | Germany | Remote

**Developer,** Appen Ltd Chatbot software development. 2020 - 2022

**Project Manager,** *UniD Formazione* □

2015 - 2018

Remote

Development, deployment and system administration for the company web applications.

Borgo Maggiore, RSM

Teacher, MIUR □

2011 - 2014

Mathematics/Logic teacher for high school and university students.

Verona, Italy

#### Languages

**Italian** Native

**English** 

**TOEFL 2020** 

#### **Education**

PhD, Università "La Sapienza"

2007 - 2010

PhD Program in Mathematical Logic | Thesis title: "A two-dimensional semantics for

Rome, Italy

natural language formalization"

Master Degree, Università Degli Studi di Genova

2002 - 2007

Italian Master Degree (Laurea Magistrale)

Genova, Italy

#### **Certificates**

**TOEFL** 

Test date: 2020

Score: 98/120 (Advanced)

**PCAP - Certified Associate in Python Programming** 

ID: 383260354

Validation: 338962730

Score: 92%

# **Projects**

# **AGReATWine,** *Contributor* □

2020 - present

Creation of a database of Italian wines included in DOCG appellations, evaluated by the three main national wine guides

# KDE, Contributor, Member ☑

2005 - present

Code, designs and translations for many desktop applications and web applications from the KDE ecosystem.

#### **ArchLinux,** *Package mantainer* □

2005 - present

Arch Linux is a Linux distribution that tries to Keep It Simple

### **GSConnect,** Contributor □

Complete implementation of KDE Connect especially for GNOME Shell.

### **InvoicePlane**, *Contributor* □

A self-hosted open source application for managing your invoices, clients and payments.

# RAMP, Contributor

Ramp is a python library for rapid prototyping of machine learning solutions. It's a light-weight pandas-based machine learning framework pluggable with existing python machine learning and statistics tools.

## **Wiki.js,** *Patch contributor* □

Wiki.js is a modern and powerful wiki app built on Node.js

# **Publications**

Collana UnidTest, Libri per la preparazione dei test di ammissione universitari 🛭